Bryn Williams

Phone: 07738337111 Github: https://github.com/bryn9696 Email: bryn2009@live.co.uk

I am an entrepreneur at heart. Since 2015 I have worked in various roles in physical education (PE) and this inspired me to start my own business, running sports clubs, in 2019. Throughout this, technology has always excited me thinking about how technologies can and do play a role in sport. As someone familiar with the problems in sport and I want to be a part of the solution, this lead me to complete the Makers academy bootcamp and retrain as a software developer. The innovation and need to problem solve in the technology industry is what appeals to me.

Projects		
Crosswordle	A web app to play a Worldle and crossword	React.js, Python, CSS, Agile,
(deployed crossword)	crossover.	Spike and Stabilise
Acebook	A web app to mimic Facebook.	Ruby on Rails, TDD, Agile, Rspec,
		Capybara, Heroku, HTML, CSS
<u>MakersBnB</u>	A web app to mimic AirBnB.	Ruby, TDD, Agile, Rspec,
		Capybara, Heroku, HTML, CSS
See more of my pr	rojects <u>here</u>	

Work Experience:

Founder and Director at Sports Specialists Limited (2018 to 2022)

Sports Specialists Limited

- Organisation: Allocating which staff were at which location and allocating lead coach's for each site to deliver exceptional sport sessions.
- Planning: Pairing coaches who could work well together to enable smooth running sessions.
- Flexibility and adaptability: Adjusting when staff were out or for any conflicts arose.
- Managing customer database: Inputting and maintaining customer information.
- Problem solving: Point of contact for staff and customers who had any problems or issues as well as being the person to sort any logistical problems. This lead to a smoother running of the company.

Sports Coach (2019 to 2021)

Royal Kent School

- Lesson planning: Required good teamwork, being coordinated with the PE team in order to bounce ideas off each
 other and create effective lessons.
- Leading sports lessons: Responsible for delivering a number of sports programs across the school. This involved innovative thinking, clear communication, leadership and problem solving skills.

Learning Support Assistant (September 2018 – August 2021)

Royal Kent School

- Small group work: Attention to detail in order to see how children were working and aiding them through their learning.

PE Gap Year Teaching Assistant (September 2015 - July 2017)

Surbiton High Boys Preparatory School

- Managing Sports Teams: Every term, I was given a team to manage for matches and tournaments. Therefore, I had to be organised in setting up training sessions, decisive in picking teams and making decisions on match days.

Education:

Makers Academy Software Development Bootcamp (October 2021 to January 2022)

- Using Ruby, I learnt to test drive development, using RSpec, through object oriented programming.
- TDD taught me how to effectively debug and refactor applications.
- Pair programming to problem solve efficiently, requiring teamwork and communication.
- As well as Ruby I have used JavaScript and React to create projects along with HTML and CSS to style the web apps. Deployed to Heroku and used Capybara, Jest and Rspec to test.

The Open University (September 2017 to July 2021)

- BSc(Hons) in Sport, Fitness and Coaching (2:1)

Hobbies:

I enjoy going to watch the football, more specifically Fulham. Along side this, I like to coach football. I also love to cook (mainly pasta), am into fitness and gaming.